MICHAEL PETER LEWIS

0409906016 | michael.lewis3126@gmail.com | Melbourne, Victoria

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

Self motivated, hardworking and eager to learn Commerce and Information Technology students with a passion for data, programming and analysis. With 6 years of workplace experience, has developed the ability to learn in rapidly changing environments and adapt to the needs of an ever growing and changing business.

WORK EXPERIENCE

WSP January 2022 - PRESENT

Business Analyst - Intern

- Facilitate client engagements to de-risk projects while delivering user focused tickets that accurately reflect requirements.
- Created functional working relationships with developers to structure process flows to support logical back end development.
- Initiate high level discussions regarding solution architecture and sprint planning to gather constructive criticism on plans.

KPMG November 2021 - January 2022

Data Analyst - Vacationer

- Developed a sequential market basket analysis model in R and SQL to predict service line trends across the company
- Created proof of concepts used to substantiate a project based on results from 400,000+ records from SQL databases.
- Developed usable and interpretable models and presentations, used to support strategic business decision making.

Woolworths December 2015 - PRESENT

Duty Manager

- Efficiently run the store night processes once managers had gone home while also filling in as a relief for managers on days.
- Resolved difficult customer situations that supervisors could not, and took reasonable steps to keep customers happy.
- Oversaw the cash handling, to ensure all cash and keys were stowed away in the safe and personally locked the store.
- Supported new line managers, in their transition into the "Duty Manager" role and carefully monitored their progress.

SalesLink Group

September 2019 - January 2021

Merchandiser

- Developed strong working relations with managers to use as leverage for clients; Achieve an unpaid 26 tower display
- Enforce strict compliance in all stores so clients are represented correctly and paid space was not disregarded by stores

EDUCATION

Monash University Expected Graduation - June 2023

Bachelor of Commerce and Information Technology majoring in Business Information Systems and Business Analytics

Camberwell Grammar School Graduated 2018

VCE Subjects: Economics, English, Global Politics, Legal Studies, Music and Maths Methods

VOLUNTEER EXPERIENCE

Cadet Leadership Courses Staff - Assistant Directing Staff (ADS)

December 2017 & 2018

- Volunteered as teaching staff for cadet leader courses over school holidays (after completing all 3 the previous years.)
- Taught the Senior Leadership Course, being in charge of the learning of 30 young cadets, designing and planning the week with two other ADS in the platoon to develop integrity, respect and leadership

PROFESSIONAL SKILLS

- Excellent soft skill, including communication skills, reading people and their body language and emotional intelligence
- Understanding of SQL, VBA, Java, and Python coding languages, and fluent in R
- Developing skills in front and back end design in my own personal website, using raw HTML, CSS and JS
- Strong analytical skills not only from a technical standpoint but also the ability to interpret and take action based on metrics